Josiah, how we doing? Can you hear us?
Yep, doing good. How are you? Excellent,
doing well. Welcome to Tampa. Uh we got
our little
here.
>> Rick, why don't you go ahead and get us
started? Hey Josiah, congratulations. Uh
just let me know what interaction you
might have had with the Bucks and and
just your reaction to coming to Tampa.
They're certainly a
a franchise that your family's familiar
with.
Yeah, no doubt. I mean, it was it was a
great visit being to meet that staff
even at the combine having my visits
with them. So, you know, just knowing
that coaching staff especially a lot of
the guys on the coaching staff who I've
known either for a long time or you
know, they have known my dad and then
especially just I lived in Tampa for a
little bit when my dad played for them.
So, kind of already knowing about the
not only just the culture, but you know,
Bucks football and being down there when
I was younger. So, you know, I'm just
excited to be able to down there and get
to work with all those guys, my
linebackers coach and just the rest of
guys on that roster.
Josiah, tell us what you think your
strengths are as a linebacker. What do
you do best at the position? Yeah, I
think without a doubt when it comes to
my strengths, that's going to be
physicality. I think as that that
position, that's a big thing just for me
and just how I was brought up. But
definitely physicality, my instincts to
be able to play my brain, try to put
myself ahead of plays and then just
being a leader, be able to communicate,
be a tone setter. You know, I think I'm
going to be a player that's not only
just going to be able to just do that,
but also be productive out there in all
phases of the game and be able to just,
you know, be someone that guys can look
at and be a alpha, be a leader, be a
green dot guy and just be able to look
at to be a not only great football
player, but a great locker room guy,
someone who's going to put the team
before himself.
Josiah, congratulations. What do you
know about What do you know about Todd
Bowles' defense?
Yeah, they like to blitz, man. They like
to blitz to get after it, man. They play
some good defense, hard-nosed defense.
And just talking to him, man, it's a
it's a great scheme, great system to be
able to fit in and, you know, they're
going to allow you to be able to show
and just showcase everything you can do
as a linebacker from all over. And I I
love that, you know, love what he's been
doing down there, man. I've been knowing
him for, you know, a long time.
Josiah, congratulations. You went to a
Clemson camp with Troy Bowles a couple
years ago. You also know Mike Caldwell
back
when your dad played in Philadelphia.
Just talk about those unique connections
that you have to the franchise.
Yeah, yeah, just knowing, you know,
Coach Bowles from when I did the camp
with his son and just knowing him ever
since then just the interactions with
him. So, that was great just being when
I met him then and
um when he just when he knew my dad and
Coach Caldwell and his family just
just being family friends with them
since for so long and knowing them when
my dad both of our parents had played
together. So, it was really cool just to
be able to not only just meet with them,
but just to be a full circle moment of
just all this time that's passed and
just knowing each other not only just
long, but you know, finally seeing each
other.
Josiah, you you played basically 2 years
of college football as a starter. Just
want to ask you, what what gave you the
confidence to to know you could go to
the next level and be drafted as high as
you were in your and play well as a pro.
Yeah, I think for me it was like, you
know, when you come to the SEC, I feel
like it's the best competition. When you
go to the SEC, and I feel like you're
able to go dominate, you know, I feel
like it's the closest thing next to
going to the NFL and I felt ready. I
felt ready to go and just I feel like
God was leading me in that direction and
praying about it and just had blessed
opportunity just to be able to come out
and, you know, just trusting him and how
my process went and I knew I felt like I
was ready and capable of just being able
to go to that next level just not only
play physically, but also mentally.
You've been lauded for your run
disruption and, you know, run stopping
skills as a linebacker. What kind of
skills go into helping you do that? And
how did you develop those skills and
kind of get the instinct for that type
of thing in the game?
Yeah, no doubt. I mean, a lot of it is
just God-given instincts and just talent
and ability that he's blessed me with to
allow me to be able to use and have my
dad in my life, you know, to be able to
help me from a young age how to use
those things, to grow up and just know
how to be a not only professional, but
to play this position. There's a lot
that comes with it. And a lot of behind
the scenes that you got to put into it
that a lot of people don't see. So, a
lot of that he's built just built up in
me just guiding me, showing me. So,
um you know, there's a lot there's a lot
with it. So, I think my strengths and
just everything that comes with it is
something that's just been molded and
bred into me since I was born.
Josiah, Bowles asks a lot of his
linebackers
coming downhill. Blitzing is something
you're really comfortable with.
Obviously, you're a beast against the
run. But as far as coverage, dropping
back, what's your comfortability there?
It's something that obviously, you know,
it's something you can improve at as as
you get into the next level, but what's
your comfortability there?
Yeah, no doubt. I think, you know, being
able to showcase everything and I think
when I get within that scheme and
coaching staff,
I'm very comfortable when it comes to
that, you know, coverage and those
aspects of whatever they're asking me to
do. And at this point in my career being
able to touch all those aspects of the
coverage or play calling or defensive
scheme. So, I think when I be able to go
there, man, just the not only coaches I
have with me, but being able to showcase
you
to my game and, you know, not only will
they see it, but the whole NFL will see
it and I'll be able to show them that
not only am I a complete player, but the
whole NFL.
Josiah, there's not many people that can
say they're the son of an NFL linebacker
and also the brother of an NFL
linebacker. For you, how has that shaped
just your football journey growing up
and
college?
Yeah, it shaped me so much from a young
age, you know, being able to see my dad
as dad and then growing up, you know,
learning more about, you know, what that
last name meant, you know, having him
as, you know, not only as a coach, as a
father, but someone that played in NFL
at a high level and then a brother that
was really good and then ultimately is
playing right now in NFL. So, you know,
it was a lot of pressure maybe when I
was younger, but I learned, you know,
you never embrace it, you always be
running from it. So, I always learned to
embrace it, put a chip on my shoulder.
And I think it's also made me into the
player I am today cuz they also helped
me. They, you know, poured into me, you
know, to be able to get to me to this
point as well and, you know, just
blessed and thankful to God that, you
know, not only they're in my life, but,
you know, they were positive influence
and people I look up to and really lean
on not only for advice just for
football, but just in life. So,
Josiah, you mentioned the, you know,
leadership traits that you bring in that
linebacker room. The Bucks have just
lost a big one in Lavonte David. So,
you just kind of to get
that linebacker room and and try to make
an impact maybe as a leader as well.
Yeah, yeah, you know, the Bucks lost a
great leader, a guy that, you know, I
think should be in the Hall of Fame and
someone that I grew up just, you know,
watching him, but just really respected
his game, the way he played, especially
as long as he did. And you know, being
able to come in as a young guy and be
able to show guys that, you know, I'm
ready to go, I'm ready to work, you
know, and just be able to come in and
be, you know, be myself, be my authentic
self, not trying to be, you know,
something I'm not and just show that I
can be a leader, you know, in my own way
and be able to come in, step in and be
someone that they look at, you know,
even if I'm being, you know, just turned
21 that, you know, I'm a leader, I can
vocalize and be I'm going to go out
there and make productive plays and be
able to look at as a alpha and as a
leader, you know, someone that they can
trust and respect at the same time
ultimately.
Josiah, when when you look at current
NFL linebackers when you're watching
tape, are there guys that that you like,
you like to emulate, that have similar
body types, strengths, skill sets to
what you have?
Um yeah, I mean, there's always, you
know, my favorite Fred whenever I can
catch his games. You know, just watching
good linebacker play. Me, I just like
seeing good linebacker play, you know,
um just across the league. So, I think
there's a lot of good linebackers across
the league that I get some really good
tape, you know, from week to week or
just got the season, you know. And but
for me, I never really had anybody I
really just say, "Hey, I just put my
game after him." You know, I think my
dad is always number one cuz that's my
dad and he played and I'm always going
to take a big portion from his game. So,
um especially my brother, too. But I
think, you know, a lot of things I work
on as a player and things I do, um you
know, you don't see too often uh
especially maybe nowadays. Um so, I'm
trying to just bring, you know, not only
just physicality back, but bring out not
only old school, but new school feel
back, bring in that dominant, you know,
force and just, you know, when when they
see the Bucks defense, you know,
I want people to feel that defense, you
know, to feel that front seven all
around cuz, you know, I don't want it to
just be one player. I want it to be the
whole defense just be a bunch of dogs
out there.
What do you know about the Bucks' first
round draft pick, Ruben Bain? How
excited are you to kind of come in and
be part of that rookie class with him?
Man, excited. I was uh I was able to
talk with him
a while back when we were on the same
visit together in Cincinnati.
Great dude, you know, I know he's fired
up. He's got a chip on his shoulder like
I got a chip on my shoulder. We're just
ready to just go show not only just, you
know, Bucks nation, but the NFL, you
know, the whole world know what we can
do.
Um and just, you know, just grateful to
for the opportunity to be able to go
there and be able to show teams.
What did Todd Bowles say if anything
about your opportunity? I mean,
obviously
they're
watching you a green dot guy.
Is that the kind of role you think you
can step in and and handle right away as
a as a 21-year-old?
Yeah, you know, just talking with Coach
Bowles and just, you know,
basically let you know, let me know like
he you know, obviously, you know, you
see they lost Lavonte David and losing a
great leader, you know, guy that was a
green dot that's been there and played a
long time. And that's a role to be able
to step in and you know, something they
always asked me and that's something
I've done since a young age of someone
that's called being able to make plays,
call plays and everything like that. So,
you know, I'm very comfortable being
able to do that
and being able to step into that role
and to, you know, do it, you know, to
the best of my ability and knowing that,
you know, they I feel like they'd be
happy with me being stepping into that
position.
And being 21 years old after playing two
seasons of college football, do you feel
like you're scratching the surface of
your potential and what you could be?
Oh, without a shadow of doubt. I'm only
scratching my surface, you know.
Um you know, I only played two seasons
and was able to play one season with
Mizzou just, you know, of just getting
there with a different scheme and I'm
just scratching the surface and once
people find out and then they see what
God put on the inside of me or what I
can truly do as a all around linebacker,
um you know,
I mean, I can they overlook, but I I can
I can only show you better I can tell
you. So, that's all I really tell
people, man. I can only show you better
I can tell you. So, I'm just going to
let time do its thing and when I get
there, just put my head down, go grind,
get to work and just try to be the best
me I can possibly that God made me to
be.
Josiah, what's your message to Bucks
fans who are who are watching this and
excited to have you in Tampa?
Man, one thing you're going to get a
player that's not only just committed
and selfless, but is going to be a
physical player and that's is to come in
and just try to you know bring a Super
Bowl. That's my ultimate goal to bring a
Super Bowl to Bucks Nation and try to be
the best version I can be for not only
just Bucks Nation but for my team, my
coaches, my family, God and you know, I
just want to come in just give you
everything I got every single day and
try to just come in and be myself, you
know, you guys lost a great one. I want
to come in and try to be even better
than that and exceed that and man, he
was a he was a great person just to be
able to watch and especially as long as
he was there.
That's fine.
All right. Thank you.
>> Congratulations to the
Appreciate it. Thank you.